A Finding Aid to the Dorothy Dehner Papers, 1920-1987 (bulk 1951-1987), in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1940-1987; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet
  - Clippings, David Smith, 1974-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Clippings, Lucille Corcos Levy, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Dehner Group Exhibitions, circa 1959-circa 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Dehner Solo Exhibitions, 1952-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Others, 1940-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Dehner Group Exhibitions, 1941-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Dehner Group Exhibitions, 1946-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Dehner Group Exhibitions, 1959-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Dehner Group Exhibitions, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Dehner Group Exhibitions, 1972-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Dehner Group Exhibitions, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Dehner Group Exhibitions, 1981-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Dehner Solo Exhibitions, 1957-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, David Smith, 1940s-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, David Smith, 1973-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Posters, Oversized, 1956-1972; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 6, Folder 1)
  - Printed Material, Miscellaneous, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Programs and Reports, 1947-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Artwork, circa 1930s-circa 1960s; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.05 Linear feet
  Art work consists of two undated etchings. One is an abstract by Dehner, which she gave, presumably as a gift, to Garnett McCoy, former Curator of the Archives of American Art. The second etching is of portraits of artists done by one another on one etching plate. Artists include Lucille Corcos by Dehner, David Smith by Lucille Corcos, Adolph Gottlieb by Edgar Levy, Edgar Levy by Esther Gottlieb, Dorothy Dehner by Adolph Gottlieb, and Esther Gottlieb by David Smith. A cat and alligator were drawn by Edgar Levy in the middle border. The etching is 91/100 and was printed by Michael Kirk on the Charles Brand Press in the Parsons School of Design Studios and seems to have also originally belonged to Garnett McCoy.
  - Etching, Abstract, circa 1930s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Etching, Artists' Portraits, Oversized, circa 1930s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 6, Folder 2)
- Photographs, 1930s-1986; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 0.15 Linear feet
  Series consists of photographs of Dehner, her friend and mentor John Graham (taken by her in the Brooklyn apartment she shared with David Smith), and her second husband Ferdinand Mann (featured with others, including Fiorello LaGuardia, Arshile Gorky, and Henry Knight, at the opening of the W.P.A. Art Gallery), as well as photographs of Dehner works from the 1950s (assembled in an album or portfolio of "Recent Works") and some later works. Also found is an abstract photograph taken by David Smith circa 1934, one of several he created using the technique of double exposure.
  - Photographs of Dehner, 1971, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Dehner's Artwork, 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Dehner's Artwork, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Dehner's Artwork, Album, 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Dehner Exhibition, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Photograph by David Smith, circa 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Photograph of David Smith Artwork, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Artwork authenticated on back of photo by Dorothy Dehner
  - Photograph of Ferdinand Mann, circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Photographs of John Graham, 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Photographs of John Graham's Artwork, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)